Hello everyone, in this video, we will learn how to correctly use the auto-adjustment and auto-adjustment function of the test suit.
First, let's learn how to create a test suit.
First, you can import an OBJ file or FBX file as a virtual model.
After importing an OBJ file, select the corresponding unit in the import window, and then click OK.
You can refer to the ratio of the characters and the ground in the video to select the unit to be imported, not too big or too small.
Next, we need a virtual model.
że we first created test suit
and test suit,
the test suit will start working as soon as to run out the total costume Beneath 这个模型创建试穿服 在创建完试穿服之后才可以去使用自動穿着或者是自动调整版片功能
what you need to notice is that the test suit will clear out the toutieing of the comfortably fully costume
so remember to zip it up so that when you select it, the costume will be emptied all.
否则当你选择创建试穿服的时候then when you pick the wide ao suit, the costume will be emptied out.
然后我们梦想惠l
风物
nothing
After talking about creating the window of the window of the window, we have to follow the size of these parts according to the high number to gradually create a 3D measurement line on the virtual model.
Click on three points on the virtual model to create a virtual model.
We will create it in slow motion.
Create the first starting point first, then click on the second point.
When clicking on the third point, we can move the mouse to refer to the preview effect.
In the confirmed position, click on the third point to form a circle.
When creating a circle measurement, press the Shift key to create a point along the level or value direction.
If your model is left and right symmetrical, then when dealing with the wrist, you can open the symmetrical creation key.
If your model is not left and right symmetrical, then we can cancel the selection of symmetry, and separate the left and right side measurements of the creation key.
Then we continue to create other measurements in accordance with the sequence.
If there is a mistake in the measurement data, or we need to adjust it, we can click on the measurement right here.
Select delete, then you can create this measurement data again.
Then if it is the model used in the video, you can make adjustments to the shoulder or some joint positions.
Then you can make adjustments to the shoulder or some joint positions.
Then we need to make adjustments to the shoulder or some joint positions.
Then we make adjustments to the shoulder or some joint positions.
In the bottom right corner, there is a leave out вариант, it is line 11 00 to the left and this is line 11 x to the left.
The left and right
will be aligned.
The left and right side is side 1.
to create these semi-transparent panels.
So after we have created all the measurements,
click on the application,
these panels will be divided together
to form a test fit.
It is very tightly attached to the virtual model.
If there are places where the virtual model penetrates,
we manually drag the panel
so that it does not have a large amount of penetration.
When the test fit is all done,
we click Save,
and save the virtual model.
After that,
every time we want to use the self-adjustment panel
or the self-adjustment function,
we will import this model.
Now you click on the 3D window,
you can choose to display the test fit of the virtual model.
Here we can see that
there is already a circle of test fits around the virtual model.
Click again,
we can choose to hide the virtual model test fit.
Because now,
there is a test fit on the model,
so we can import a test fit of the virtual model
to perform other operations.
In the file folder in the software,
all these virtual models have test fit information.
In order to check whether this virtual model has test fit information,
we can go to the virtual model display column
to find the display virtual model test fit.
After opening it,
we will see the red test fit.
This is the test fit information of the virtual model itself.
Why do we have test fit information in the pre-set file folder?
Because these clothes are on the pre-set virtual model
provided by our software that has test fit information.
Before this suit is simulated without pressing the control key,
it always carries the original test fit information.
So we can compare the test fit information of the virtual model
to the test fit information of the virtual model
to perform automatic wear or automatic adjustment.
These are all based on these two files.
They all protect their own test fit information.
At this time,
if we click on automatic wear,
the suit will not calculate any adjustment,
just wear on the virtual model.
And because it has remodeled the calculation,
so the test fit information it carries now
is also the test fit information of this new model.
Press Ctrl Z.
Now we go back to the time when the suit
still carries the previous test fit information.
At this time,
we press Shift F to open the arrangement point.
Here we manually arrange the version,
adjust its arrangement value,
do not have a difference with the virtual model,
and then arrange the front and back pieces separately.
Then we press the control key to simulate.
At this time,
although we do not use the automatic wear function,
because we have already recalculated,
so this suit still retains the test fit information of this virtual model.
After confirming that the suit has the test fit information,
you can save it as a suit in the upper left corner
to save the suit with the test fit information
and then use it.
Then let's take a look at
the automatic wear or automatic adjustment function
that cannot be used under what circumstances.
First of all, here,
I have a suit with test fit information,
but I choose to import an OBJ model
as a virtual model.
Because when you import the OBJ model,
it will not automatically create a test fit.
So at this time,
we will lack the test fit information of the virtual model.
If the test fit information of the virtual model is missing,
at this time,
we click on the automatic wear or automatic adjustment version,
it will pop up a prompt.
This prompt means that
your virtual model needs to create a test fit first
and register it.
Similarly, we cannot use the automatic adjustment version
because this virtual model
does not have any test fit information.
Only clothes with test fit information are not enough.
So if we skip this prompt,
we need to add a virtual model
with test fit information in the upper left corner.
Then let's look at another case.
If our virtual model,
she has a test fit information,
but the clothes we loaded,
she did not have a test fit information
saved for the second time.
Let's see how it works.
Here we are in the 3D window,
choose to open the display,
clothes, test fit.
We will see that
the new set of clothes
does not have a test fit.
At this time,
if we go to use the automatic adjustment version
or the automatic wear function,
because of the lack of clothes,
there is no test fit information.
So it doesn't work.
It will pop up a prompt,
prompt you to say
that this costume must have a test fit information.
Sometimes if we download the costume
or the costume we created,
it does not have a test fit information,
you can use our
virtual model file in the library window
to bring these pre-set virtual models
in the folder.
Let's wear this costume first.
Just because our software
brings their own virtual models,
they all have test fit information.
So let's wear this costume
on this virtual model first.
Let the clothes have test fit information,
left-hand corner,
and then save it.
After that,
we can use these functions.
Here we press the control key
to simulate the test fit information
of the virtual model with the costume.
To confirm,
we can select the test fit
to display the costume
in the test fit menu
in the 3D window.
If we want to use these functions,
of course,
don't forget that
if we want to use these functions,
we have to save this costume
in the left-hand corner first,
and then upload it to our
virtual model with test fit information.
Use the virtual model
that the software brings
to wear the costume.
There is another advantage
to this method
of wearing the costume
with test fit information.
Because the virtual model
in the software
can be edited
in the virtual model editor at the top.
We can edit the size of the virtual model
in the virtual model editor.
When we have edited
the size of the virtual model,
the test fit of the virtual model
will also change
with the size of the virtual model.
In addition,
if we use the Move Target function,
that is,
by inserting the second OBJ model
to transform the first OBJ model,
then the test fit information
on the original OBJ model
will be transformed.
If you don't know
about the Move Target function itself,
you can take a look at
our previous tutorial video
about virtual models.
Next,
let's take a look at
the correct way
to use the automatic wearing
or automatic adjustment
version.
First of all,
let's import a virtual model
with test fit information
and then we open
a costume
with test fit information.
What I import is
the virtual model
that we just wore
on the virtual model
that we brought
on the software
and saved the test fit information
for the second time.
The second time
we save the test fit information
of this set of costumes
for the first time.
Then we can use
the automatic adjustment version
or the automatic wearing function.
First of all,
let's take a look
at the automatic wearing.
Although this set of costumes
may be more complicated
and the posture
is not exactly the same
as the virtual model
posture now,
but you can see
that after we use
the automatic wearing function,
all the costumes
will be fully worn
on the virtual model.
However,
because there is a certain
body size gap,
the wearing effect
of the costume
is not very good.
At this time,
we can use the automatic adjustment
version function.
This function will
calculate their body size
difference
and automatic adjustment
version
according to
your virtual model
test fit
and the costume
test fit.
The higher the value
of the version
of the version,
the more it can maintain
all the original
curves of the curve.
If you choose to
choose to keep
the original curve,
the size of the
sticker will not
be automatically
released.
After clicking
confirm,
we need to wait
for its calculation.
After the calculation is completed,
the size of the costume
will be modified
and the costume
will automatically
be worn
on the new virtual model.
This tutorial video
ends here.
See you next time.
Bye bye.